COREY CROOKS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT



412-559-9875



Corey.C.Crooks@gmail.com



Cranberry Township, PA



github.com/C3rooks



In Linkedin.com/crookscorey

EDUCATION

B.S Computer Science

University of Pittsburgh 2009-2014

A.S Applied Science

Community College of AC 2006-2009

SKILLS

Java Development

C# Development

C Development

SQL (Oracle, SQL Server)

IOS/Android Development

PHP/JS/CSS/HTML

ETL/SSIS

Algorithms/Algorithm Design

Quality Analysis

Windows/Unix/Mac OS

PROFILE

Highly motivated, highly skilled software engineer with seven years of experience in software development. Algorithm design for automating process flow expertise. Versatile, quick-learner, willing to embrace new challenges. Excellent knowledge in computer science and driven to succeed.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

UPMC Corporate / 2014 - Present

- Design and develop new applications for daily automation
- Develop EOB's to send out to patients on a month to month
- Develop a data extract (C#) to merge multiple code bases into one specific design and provide regulatory maintenance on the application.
- Develop an ETL process for Oracle to SQL data migration (SSIS/Informatica).
- Develop a parser program to pull data from a text file into a DB.
- Develop workflows for each invoice/EOB.

Database Engineer

KIT Solutions / 2013 - 2014

- Developed ETL projects to enhance/produce data migration.
- Constructed a full range of SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) reports, from ad-hoc to parameterized multi-use designs. Use of Gemini Tracking system to develop and fixed issues.
- Back-End database changes, stored proc updates.

Software Engineering Internship

Pressley Ridge / 2013 - 2014

- Created, delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support a high-availability internet site with various internal application.
- Drafted comprehensive reports to document bugs and design flaws.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.